"犯罪心理"前情回顧
Previously on criminal minds...
惡魔獵手 波士頓惡魔獵手?
The reaper. The boston reaper?
如果你停止追捕我 我就不再"獵殺"他們
If you stop hunting me, i'll stop hunting them.
我從不妥協 我專門追捕你這種人
I don't make deals. I'm the guy who hunts guys like you.
你會後悔的
You'll regret this.
醒醒 Derek 是時候去死了
Wake up,derek. It's time to die.
George Foyet就是惡魔獵手 我的警徽呢?
George foyet is the reaper. Where's my badge?
Foyet逃跑了
Foyet escaped.
監獄警衛發現他在牢房埵R血抽搐
Guards found him in his cell vomiting blood and convulsing.
然後趕緊把他送去監獄醫院
They rushed him to the prison hospital.
他們會找到他 對嗎? 不 找不到的
They're gonna find him, right? No,they're not.
你應該同意做交易的
You should have made a deal.
Harney北大街附近各單位請注意 Harney北大街751號發生槍擊
All units in the vicinity of north harney boulevard, shots fired at 751 north harney.
重複 各單位注意 Harney北大街751號發生槍擊
Repeat,all units, shots fired at 751 north harney.
我們手頭沒案子辦 叫我們到犯罪現場來幹嘛?
We're not working a case. Why call us to a crime scene?
我還以為你知道原因
I was hoping you knew.
JJ說警方告知她案子非常緊急
Jj said the police told her it was urgent.
最好如此 處理完加拿大案子後 才剛睡了4個小時
4 hours of sleep after what we went through in canada,it better be.
你們已經到了
Oh,you guys are already here.
你們記得Walker探員嗎?
You guys remember detective walker?
謝謝你們的到來
Thanks for being here.
我知道你們都沒怎麼休息
I understand none of you are working on much rest.
受害者是什麼人?
Who's the victim?
他叫Nelson Martinez
His name is nelson martinez.
據我們瞭解 他應聲去開門
From what we can figure, he answered his door,
被槍口頂著退到房間 胸部中槍
was forced into the apartment at gunpoint and then shot in the chest.
現場處理得很草率
It was all pretty sloppy.
無意冒犯 但我不明白找我們幹嘛
No disrespect, but I don't understand why you need us here.
兩天前 本地的Tom Barton醫生 在醫院收到一封寄給他的留言
2 days ago,a local doctor named tom barton found a note addressed to him at the hospital.
上面說寫信人正謀劃殺害他兒子
It said the person was planning to kill his son.
如果Barton醫生企圖將兒子藏起來 每天將有一個人在其住所身亡
If dr. Barton tried to keep his boy hidden, one person would die every day in his place.
你認為與此案有聯繫?
And you think this is connected?
留言署名是LC
The note is signed l.C.
昨天已有一人遇害
Yesterday we had another victim.
其住所外有多處槍擊
Multiple gunshots outside the apartment.
兇手用白粉筆在屍體旁寫下LC
The shooter wrote l.C.In white chalk next to the body.
現在 除非Barton醫生送子入虎口 那每天都會有一名新受害者
Now,unless dr. Barton puts his son in harm's way, we're going to keep having a victim a day.
Barton醫生現在在哪兒?
Where's barton now?
他在家 還不知道這名受害者的事
He's at home. He doesn't know about this victim yet.
Hotch呢? 他沒接電話 可能是調成振動了
Where's hotch? He's not answering his cell. I assume it's on vibrate.
他醒來後會收到信息的
He'll get the message when he wakes up.
再打給他 讓他去Barton家與我們會合
Try him again. He can meet us at barton's house.
我是特別督察探員Aaron Hotchner
You've reached supervisory special agent aaron hotchner.
有事請留詳細信息 謝謝
Please leave a detailed message. Thank you.
Hotch 還是我JJ
Hotch,jj again.
請你到弗吉尼亞州McLean市 Kensington路120號找我們
Listen,we're gonna need you to meet us at an address in mclean,virginia120 kensington road.
收到後回我電話
Call me when you get this.
Barton醫生 你兒子現在在哪兒?
Dr. Barton, where is your son right now?
我叫他待在自己房間 你怎麼跟他說的?
Um,i asked him to stay up in his room. And what did you tell him?
我說我在醫院收到恐嚇
I told him that there was a threat against me at the hospital.
我說這並未引起警方重視 但他們希望我在家待幾天
I told him the police didn't take it seriously but that they wanted me to stay here for a few days
所以我想讓他陪著我
and that I wanted to have him with me.
Jeffrey的媽媽呢?
And jeffrey's mother?
她在他10歲時去世了 乳癌
She died when he was 10. breast cancer.
真會有人傷害Jeffrey嗎?
Would someone really hurt jeffrey?
已有兩人遇害 送留言的人絕非戲言
2 people are dead already. Whoever sent that note is obviously serious.
如果我不讓Jeffrey離開房子 就會再有人遇害?
And if I don't let jeffrey out of the house, then another person's gonna die?
眼下我們不得不認為他會繼續殺戮
Right now we have to assume that he will keep killing.
我兒子才15歲 我明白
My son is 15 years old. I understand.
我不能讓他置身危險
I cannot put him in danger.
我們沒讓你這麼做
We are not asking you to.
而且即使你願意
And even if you were willing,
我們也不會明知他會危及他人 還把他送去學校的
we couldn't send him to school knowing he would endanger every student in the building.
我們現在要做的是 仔細核查一切已知信息
What we need to do now is go over everything we know,
弄清他如何與你扯上關係
piece together how this person fits into your life.
我想不出有誰想要殺Jeffrey
Well,iiI can't think of anyone who would want to kill jeffrey.
不論是誰寫的 他都是衝你來的 這是私人恩怨
Whoever wrote that note was putting you on noticethis is personal.
他希望你記起他是誰 而在此之前
He wants you to remember who he is, and until that happens,
他是不會善罷甘休的
he hasn't accomplished what he set out to do.
我知道你已經回答過了 但請你再想想
I know you've been asked this before, but,please, think again
你認識名字縮寫是LC的人嗎?
do you know anyone with the initials l.C.
我找遍了所有日程 郵件 病歷 都沒有
I've looked everywhereday planner,emails, patient lists. There's no one.
你有沒注意到什麼人監視你
Have you noticed anyone who might have been watching you,
在醫院或是住宅鄰近區域?
either at the hospital or here in the neighborhood?
我...抱歉
I... I'm sorry.
兩名受害者都是 40多歲的西班牙裔男性
Both the victims he's killed have been hispanic men in their 40s.
你最近有符合該描述的病患嗎?
Have you had a patient recently that fits the description?
我是華盛頓的外科醫生
I'a trauma surgeon in d.C.
我有數不清的病人 各種特徵
I have endless patients, all demographics.
我們需要你最近所有手術的資料
We're gonna need records of all your recent surgeries.
當然可以
Of course.
我給Garcia打電話
I'll call garcia.
我不明白 如果他是衝我來的 為什麼不直接來殺我?
Ii don't understand. If he's mad at me, why not just kill me?
JJ 有Hotch的回音嗎?
Jj. Is there any word from hotch?
還沒有
No,nothing.
這可不像他的風格 是 我知道
That's not like him. Yeah,i know.
是我的電話
It's mine.
喂? 爸爸?
Hello? Dad?
Jeffrey? 請不要生我的氣
Jeffrey? Please don't be mad at me.
怎麼回事? 你還好嗎?
Whatwhat's happening? Are you ok?
Jeffrey 發生什麼事了?
Jeffrey,what's going on?
說話啊
Talk to me.
他不在樓上
He's not up here.
Jeffrey 你在哪兒?
Jeffrey,where are you?
我在學校 我沒事
I'm at school. I'm ok.
告訴警察我沒事
Please tell the police that i'm ok.
Jeffrey 我愛你
JeffreyI love you.
犯罪心理 第五季 第1集
Criminal Minds Season05 Episode01 Nameless, Faceless
卡爾·克勞斯說"弱者在決策前遲疑"
Karl krauss said, "a weak man has doubts before a decision.
上世紀上半葉最傑出 德語作家和語言大師之一
"強者則反之"
A strong man has them afterwards."
Barton醫生 拜託你 你必須回去
dr. Barton,please. You need to go back inside.
我也要去 我要去接我兒子
I'm coming with you. I'm gonna get my son.
先生 現在沒人帶走你的兒子
Sir,right now nobody is getting your son.
Prentiss探員會向你解釋的
Agent prentiss will explain it.
我要的不是解釋 我要去接Jeffrey
I don't need an explanation. I'm getting jeffrey.
你現在仔細聽好
You need to listen right now.
一旦你兒子離開這房子 學校就是他最安全的地方
Once your son left this house, the safest place for him to be is at that school.
我們可以監控所有的進出口
We can control access in and out.
一放學 Walker探員就會組織疏散
Detective walker will organize an evacuation as soon as the school day is done.
要是現在引起恐慌 而不明嫌犯就在外面 很多孩子會死
But if we incite a panic now and the unsub is outside, a lot of kids are gonna die.
那要是兇手已經在校內了呢?
What if the killer is already at the school?
我們也會在堶
Then we'll be there,too.
交給我們來做
Let us do our job.
Jeffrey很有頭腦 他不是有意讓自己身處危險
Jeffrey knows better than this. He doesn'tutimself in danger.
我想他只是想做對的事
I think he's just trying to do the right thing.
他知道父親是做什麼謀生的
He sees what his father does for a living.
這正是他挽救生命的方式
This is his way of trying to save lives,too.
你們會在那兒吧? 是的
You'll be there? Yes.
告訴他我沒生他的氣 告訴他我愛他 還有...
Tell him i'm not mad at him. Tell him I love him, and,uh...
我為他感到驕傲 我們會的
I'm proud of him. We will.
他是中心城區醫院的外科醫生
This guy's a trauma surgeon working a major metropolitan area.
我們要找的可是幾千例手術啊
We are talking thousands of surgeries.
縮小到近6個月內
Confine it to the last 6 months.
還是有幾百例啊 我知道
That's still hundreds. I know.
好吧 你是要個人信息還是完整病歷?
Ok,do you want biographical information or full medical charts?
你能弄到完整的病歷?
Can you get the full medical charts?
知道嗎 別看你是聰明孩子 也還是會問一堆傻問題
You know,for a smart boy, you still ask a lot of dumb questions.
幾秒鐘後發給你 嘿 Garcia
You'll have them in seconds. Hey,garcia.
在呢 我的寶貝
Yes,my love.
Hotch聯繫你了嗎?
Has hotch checked in with you?
他不和你們在一塊兒? 也許在來的路上吧
He's not with you? He's probably on his way.
謝謝你 拜
Uh,thanks for everything. Bye.
她會把文件發給我們 我們可以在這兒打印出來
She's going to email the files. We'll print them out from here.
我可以要辦公室把文件送來
I could have my office send over the files.
不 不用 相信我們 這樣更快
No,no,trust us, this is faster.
我們要挖掘你生活的每個細節 找出這件事的起因
We need to dig through your life and try to figure out why this is happening.
我們從最近的病例著手查起
Let's start with the most recent cases first,
惹惱這傢伙的導火索 很可能就在文件
something set this guy off,and odds are it's in your files.
我得通知所有家長
I need to notify all the parents.
我們認為那不明智
We think that's a mistake.
我要對這些孩子的安全負責 正是
I'm in charge of keeping these kids safe. Exactly.
等到公車和家長來接這些孩子 學校會很自然地放學關門
And there's a natural end to this day, when buses and parents come to pick these kids up.
不論他是誰 絕不是高效的射手
Whoever's doing this is not an effectual shooter.
他行兇時很草率
His killings are sloppy.
所以萬一引起恐慌 很多人可能會在對峙時受傷
So if there's a panic, a lot of people could be caught in the crossfire.
你們就不能帶Jeffrey回家嗎?
Can't you just take jeffrey home?
如我們這麼做 被嫌犯看到 其他人就會被害
If we do that and the unsub is watching, someone else is gonna be killed.
那怎麼辦?
Then what?
我們會封鎖除前門外的所有進出口
We lock up every filter point except the front door.
沒人能進來 就說這是學校規定 不容質疑
Nobody comes in. We say it's school policy. No questions.
有人要見學生 我們就帶孩子去見他
And if someone needs to see a student, we bring the kids to them.
我需要一份校內目前 所有人員名單和員工資料
I'll need a complete list and employment records of everyone already inside the building.
我會帶保安作好佈置 守住所有出口
I'll brief your security guards and take care of all of the exits.
然後你要分小組召集教職員 帶他們來見我
After that,i need you to gather the faculty into small groups and bring them to me.
就當例行公事
Treat it as routine.
還有 你要盡可能自然地 把Jeffrey從教室叫出來
And in the meantime, I need you to get jeffrey out of class as casually as possible.
你能做到嗎?
Can you do that?
Jeffrey Barton 跟我出來一下
Jeffrey barton. Can I see you for a moment?
嘿 Jeffrey 我叫Derek Morgan 是FBI
Hey,jeffrey. My name's derek morgan. I'm with the fbi.
我看到你在我家客廳
I saw you in my living room.
聽著 我首先想知道 你有把這件事告訴其他人嗎?
Listen,the first thing I need to know is if you've told anyone about what's happening?
沒有
No.
回教室去 不得閒逛
Back to class. No loitering.
Jeffrey 你確定?
Jeffrey,you're sure?
因為即使一條短信 都會讓這個地方雞犬不寧
Because even just one text message could set this place off.
我確定
I'm sure.
很好 我們會保證你安全的 孩子
All right,that's good. We're gonna keep you safe,kid.
但首先 你要保持冷靜
But in order to do that, you're gonna have to stay calm.
你還必須得相信我 明白嗎?
And you're also gonna have to trust me. You understand?
每次你邁出教室 我都會在這
Every time you step out of class, I will be right here.
就像某個和Findlay校長在走廊的人
Now,it's gonna look like i'm just another adult in the hallway with principal findlay,
但我會看著你
but I got your back.
我爸爸還好嗎?
Is my dad ok?
他知道你想做正確的事
He knows you were just trying to do the right thing.
他只想把你安全帶回家
He just wants to get you home safe.
你認為有人想殺死我去報復他?
Do you think somebody's trying to kill me to get back at him?
有這種可能
It is possible.
知道原因嗎?
Do you know why?
這正是我們想搞明白的
That's what we need to figure out.
咱精力集中看看留言
Let's concentrate on the note.
首先 我們知道他是名男性
For starters, we know that he's male.
你怎麼能肯定?
How can you be sure?
女性會在留言堨[入形容詞 和描述細節的內容
Women tend to add adjectives and very specific details to their notes.
這個沒有這類現象
This has none of those.
男性通常比較直接 第一句"我打算殺死你兒子"
Males are also more direct. First sentence"i plan to kill your son."
他們的留言更多以自己為中心 而不是他們的留言對像
and their notes tend to be more about themselves than the person they're writing to.
"我每天都在看著你" "我要親眼看你失去一切"
"i watched you every day." "i will watch you lose everything."
我們知道 他在監視你和你兒子
we know he surveilled you and your son,
也就是說 他要麼很富有不用上班 要麼就正處於失業狀態
which means he either has enough money to be away from a regular job or he's currently unemployed.
他很可能是位父親 顯然他很悲傷
He's most likely a father. He's clearly grieving.
他要採取非常手段讓你"感同身受"
He's taken great measures to make sure you feel his pain.
先從涉及青少年死亡的病例入手 還有所有家人情緒激動的
Let's start with cases involving teenagers killed, but also anyone with a strong family presence.
你兒子15歲 不表示他孩子一定同歲
Just because your son is 15, that doesn't necessarily mean that his child is the same age.
你們是不是接觸過很多這種案子 別人威脅要對你下手的案子?
Have you had a lot of cases like this, where someone taunts you with what they're gonna do?
一些
A few.
結果都是怎樣?
And how did they end?
求你了
Please.
借警察之手自殺似乎是 他們求得認可和結束所有痛苦
Suicide by cop seems to be an effective way for them to make their point,
最行之有效的辦法
while ending their suffering all at once.
Jeffrey再過5小時就放學了
Jeffrey is leaving school in 5 hours.
我們沒辦法在這麼短時間內 看完所有的病人資料
There's no way we can get through all these patients in this time.
起碼我們已經縮小範圍了
Well,now,we've narrowed it down already.
但我們還有100個
And we still have 100 left.
抱歉 不是我無情 但在急診室工作 根本記不住病人的名字
I'm sorry,i don't mean to be callous, but when you work in the e.R.,you don't remember names.
做完一個手術 然後做下一個
You operate and you move on.
他說的對 就這麼點時間 要側寫的東西太多了
He's right. There are too many files here for us to profile in such a short period of time.
呃 我可以去趟Hotch家 半小時能回來
Um,i can get to hotch's and get back here in half an hour.
他是誰? 是我們的老大
Who's that? He's our supervisor.
我們今天本來休息的
We weren't supposed to work today.
聯繫不到他
We're having trouble getting ahold of him.
但我們需要更多人手
But we need more eyes.
留言上沒說今天殺死Jeffrey 寫著
The note doesn't say that he'll kill jeffrey today, it says,
"不是今天 就是明天或後天"
"if not today, tomorrow or the next day."
就算他今天能安全回家
let's say he gets home safe.
你們又能在這守護他多久?
How long will you all be around to make sure he's ok?
我們度過今天再說吧
Let's just get through today.
Hotch? 是我 Emily
Hotch? It's meemily.
加班時間 我是Penelope
Overtime shift. Penelope speaking.
Garcia 是Emily 你認真的聽著
Garcia,it's emily. I need you to listen really carefully.
Hotch出事了
Something's happened to hotch.
什麼意思? 出事了?
What do you mean,something?
我不知道 我在他家 他不在 而且地上有血跡
I don't know. I'm in his place. He's not here, but there's blood.
噢 天哪
Oh,my god.
我要你馬上派警察 和FBI技術人員來這
I need you to send police and fbi techs here right away.
有空的都叫過來
Everyone available.
要發全境通告嗎?
Uh,do we need an apb?
通告找Hotch就行 我看過前門 他的車還在
Only on hotch. I checked out front. His car's still here.
他被人綁架了? 我不知道
Someone took him? I don't know.
這埵釵撣 但我不確定是誰的
There's blood,but I can't be sure whose it is.
派人過來就對了
Just get people here.
好的 我會派支軍隊過去
Ok,i'm sending an army.
Garcia Reid在等我回去 我會告訴他 但是你不能告訴其他人
Garcia,i'm gonna have to tell reid because he's expecting me back, but you can't tell the others.
他們不能分心 好的 好的
They cannot be distracted. Ok. Ok.
什麼? 你 你說什麼?
What? Whatwhat are you talking about?
怎麼回事? 有關Jeffrey的?
What's going on? Is this about jeffrey?
不 不 不相關的
No,no,it's unrelated.
我們沒剩下幾個小時了
We only have a few hours left here.
真的很抱歉 我必須接這通電話 好嗎?
I'm really sorry, I have to take this phone call,ok?
現在還有什麼事比我兒子更重要?
What could be more important than my son right now?
我保證 一會就好 拜託了 我發誓
I assure you, this will take one second. Please,i promise.
好吧
Fine.
牆上有一個大洞
There's a huge hole in the wall.
很可能是點44口徑 但洞周圍沒有帶血組織
Ab a .44, but there's no blood fineor tissue spray around it.
知道他怎麼出去的嗎?
Any idea how he got out?
他中槍的話 地上沒有拖曳痕跡
If he was shot, there are no drag marks.
但是可以用東西把人包起來
But a body could have been wrapped in something.
局堛漣瑋N人員趕去了嗎?
And bureau techs are on the way?
隨時會到
Any second.
好吧 把你看到的都寫下來 回去後我們再分析你的記錄
All right,um,write down everything you see and we'll profile from your notes when you get back.
Barton醫生怎麼樣了?
How's dr. Barton?
這埵酗@大堆案例要看過
It's a huge list of cases to go through with him.
好吧 別擔心這 有我在 你集中注意力
Ok,don't worry about here. I've got this. Just stay focused.
好的 你也是
All right. You,too.
Barton醫生? 很抱歉
Uh,dr. Barton? Sorry about that.
Prentiss探員被緊急調走了
Agent prentiss has been called away on an emergency.
開什麼玩笑
You gotta be kidding me.
我相信我們兩人能行的 好嗎?
I'm confident that the two of us can do this together right now. All right?
他殺害西班牙男性作為替代品
We know he's been killing hispanic males as surrogates.
你病例分類做好了嗎? 是的
Did you separate the case files? Yeah.
有多少個手術符合條件?
All right,how many of the surgeries fit the criteria?
82個
Um,82.
好吧 我問你
all right. Now let me ask you this.
那些手術的當天 你還做了其他手術的有幾個?
On how many of those dates did you operate on somebody else as well?
75個
75.
有病人死在手術台上嗎?
did any of those patients die on the table?
10個 不 等等 11個
10. um,no,wait. 11.
11個 我們就從這媔}始 這整件事和選擇有關
11. that's where we start. This whole thing is about choice.
他用兒子來要挾你做抉擇 因為上一次選擇擺在你面前
He's forcing you to play god with your son because the last time you had a choice,
你的決定毀了他
your decision devastated him.
我是個醫生 救死扶傷而已
I'm a doctor. I save people.
他不關心這個
It doesn't matter to him.
他關心的只是你沒選擇另一個人
All that matters to him is that you had an alternative and you didn't take it.
哪些手術中有20歲以下的病人?
Now,how many of those surgeries involve patients under 20?
6個 總有槍傷病人送來 大部分都是幫派人物
6. we get a lot of shootings, mostly gang related.
有哪個混混或家人威脅過你?
Has a gang member or family member ever threatened you?
沒有 失去親人時 首先感到不知所措和崩潰
No,uh,at first when you lose someone it's mostly confusion and devastation.
其後才是憤怒
The anger comes later.
有六天給西班牙男性做手術
All right,we have 6 dates where you operated on an hispanic male
且同一晚 有20歲不到的病人去世
on the same night a patient under 20 died.
我要把這些姓名和日期讀給你聽
What i'm gonna do is i'm gonna read the names and dates
把你能記得的都告訴我 好嗎?
and you tell me anything you can remember,ok?
好的
Ok.
好吧 我們從1月22日開始
All right,let's start with january 22nd.
Tyler Hayes 多處槍傷
Tyler hayes, multiple gunshot wounds.
2月13日 Brian Douglas 肇事逃逸受害者 主動脈撕裂
February 13th, brian douglas, hitandrun victim, lacerated aorta.
不是 3月15日 Devon Marks 吸毒過量
No. March 15th, devon marks, heroin overdose.
Angela Harris 也是車禍 腦溢血死亡
Angela harris, another car accident, single vehicle, bleeding into her brain.
我...這沒用 如果被威脅過 我會記得的
I... This is no use. I would remember if I was threatened.
有人問起過你的家庭嗎?
Did any of them ask you about your family?
我們還有時間
We have time.
好吧
Ok.
我和Walker探員談過 3:10放學
I talked to detective walker. Final bell's at 3:10.
3點整他會帶一隊特警就位 護送學生出校
he's gonna have a s.W.A.T.Unit in place at exactly 3:00 to escort kids out.
我們需要你在2:45集合學生
We'll need you to gather the students at 2:45.
現在就可以
this could all be happening now.
如果不明嫌犯看見我們提早疏散 他肯定會去殺害另一個市民
If the unsub sees us evacuate early, we feel certain he'll kill another random citizen.
我們這一天的努力就白費了
And this also buys us a day to try and discover his identity.
所以我們用校車來疏散
So we'll have school buses for evacuation.
老師可以通知來接孩子的家長
Teachers can brief parents who are here to pick up their kids.
關鍵是把Jeffrey隔離開 避免造成他人恐慌
The key is to keep jeffrey isolated and avoid panic with the other students.
做到的話 大家都能平安離開
If we can do that, everybody gets out of here safe.
你交叉核查過這堛漱u作人員 是否和Barton有過節嗎?
Have you crosschecked all the records of employees in the building against dr. Barton?
Garcia在查
Garcia's on it.
Emily 不是
Emily. No.
抱歉 小寶貝 是我這老男人 你運氣不佳哈
Sorry,baby girl, just little old me. You're out of luck.
哦 抱歉
Right. Sorry.
你查完工作人員的背景資料了嗎?
Did you finish the background check on everyone in the building?
是的 沒危險人物 沒重罪犯 沒和Barton有關係的
Yeah. Uh,no red flags, no felonies, no connection to barton.
好的 這就好
Ok,well,that's good.
好了 聽著 我得掛了 要響鈴了
All right,listen,i gotta go. There's about to be a bell.
好的 注意安全
All right. Be safe.
一切都還好吧? 是的 噢 是的 我只是累了
Everything ok? Yeah. Oh,yeah, i'm just tired.
嗯 知道 把這孩子安全帶回家 我們就都能睡覺了
Yeah,i hear you. Let's just get this kid home safe and we can all sleep.
好的
Right.
打擾下
Excuse me.
我是來見Findlay校長的
I'm supposed to meet with principal findlay.
能告訴我她辦公室在哪媔?
Can you tell me where her office is?
喬治城醫院
Georgetown hospital.
你好 我是Penelope Garcia  FBI
My name's penelope garcia. I'm from the fbi.
有沒有名叫Aaron Hotchner的探員 送到你們急診室?
I was calling to see if an agent aaron hotchner had been admitted to the emergency room?
特別督察探員Aaron Hotchner
Supervisory special agent aaron hotchner.
Hotchner...Aaron
Hotchner,aaron.
我想知道他是否被送到急診室或...
I wanted to see if he had been admitted or if...
是 他是FBI探員
Yeah,he's an fbi agent.
什麼時候?
What... When was that?
好的 謝謝
Ok. Thank you.
天哪
Oh,my god.
說吧 Garcia
Talk to me,garcia.
我打給各家醫院 看Hotch是否進了急診室
Ok,ii called hospitals to see if hotch had gotten himself admitted to an emergency room.
然後? 病人名單上沒有 但有人把一無名傷者 送到聖塞巴斯蒂安醫院
And? He's not listed as a patient, but someone dropped a john doe off at st.Sebastian hospital,
那人名為FBI探員Derek Morgan
and that someone's name was fbi agent derek morgan.
這不可能啊 我知道 會不會他們把證件弄混了?
It doesn't make sense. I know. Do you think they got their credentials mixed up?
是惡魔獵手
The reaper.
Foyet拿走了Morgan的證件
Foyet took morgan's creds.
那為什麼送他去急診室?
Why would he drop him off at the e.R.?
你剛剛說哪家醫院?
What hospital did you say again?
聖塞巴斯蒂安醫院
St.Sebastian hospital.
我到了再打給你 好
I'll call you with an update when I get there. Yeah.
我不明白 這些手術相隔幾個小時
I don't understand. These surgeries are all hours apart.
我沒有在病患中做選擇
I didn't have to choose between patients.
如果兇手是因為我的選擇而報復 這堶惜ㄦ|有符合的
If he's punishing me for my choices, none of these fit.
再看看字條 和病例的措辭比照一下
All right, look at the note again and compare against the wording on the charts.
通常嫌犯會不自覺的通過措辭 再現當時的情況
A lot of times an unsub will unconsciously mirror the wording of situations.
想起什麼嗎?
You remember something?
我不確定 那時新年剛過
Uh,i don't know. It was right after new year's.
有場車禍 其中一名傷者是西班牙人
There was a car accident. One of the victims was hispanic.
新年...
New year's...
1月3日 兩車相撞 你給Hector Ledezma做了手術
January 3rd, there's a 2car collision, you operated on a hector ledezma.
那天晚上你只有這一個手術
That was your only surgery that night.
Ledezma太太?
Mrs. Ledezma?
撞擊導致病人腎臟破裂 大量失血
The collision lacerated his kidney. He lost a lot of blood.
但我們修補了破裂處
But we were able to repair the damage.
過段時間 他會康復的
So,it'll take some time, but he'll be just fine.
那我兒子呢? 抱歉?
What about my son? I'm sorry?
Jason Meyers 18歲 也是車禍受害者
Jason meyers. He's 18. he was in the accident.
你兒子送來醫院時已經死了
Your son was dead when he arrived here.
原來是因為我沒給那孩子做手術
That's because I dt operate on the boy.
他們告訴我他還有呼吸
They told me he's breathing.
那是給他帶了生命維持設備 但...
He's been put on life support. But,um...
但是他已腦死亡 我很抱歉
I'm afraid he no longer has brain function. I'm very sorry.
你根本沒想給他手術 已經太遲了
You're not even gonna operate. It's too late.
你根本不知道他是誰 還要看病例
You don't even know who he was. She had to give you the chart.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你有孩子嗎? 有個兒子
Do you have children? A son.
如果一個醫生拒絕救你兒子 你會對他說什麼?
What would you say to a doctor who wouldn't even try to save him?
很抱歉 我知道這難以接受 但我真的無能為力
I'm sorry. I know it's hard to understand, believe me, but there is nothing I can do.
Garcia 搜索一名叫Jason Meyers的病患
Garcia,i need you to find a patient in the system named jason meyers.
1月3日入院 使用生命維持設備 不
He was admitted january 3rd, on life support. Oh,no.
怎麼了?
What?
3天前他被撤掉呼吸機並正式宣佈死亡
He was taken off the ventilator and declared legally dead 3 days ago.
他爸爸是誰?
Who's his father?
Patrick Meyers 45歲
Yeah,uh,patrick meyers, age 45.
馬上把照片發到學校 他就是嫌犯
get a photo into the school immediately. I think he's our unsub.
好 我馬上發
Ok. Yeah. It's on its way.
他挨了9刀 但都沒傷到主動脈
He was stabbed 9 times, but no major arteries were hit.
他能活命簡直是奇跡
It's a miracle he's alive.
他什麼時候能醒?
When will he wake up?
麻醉1小時內消退
The anesthesia should wear off within the hour.
到時就會醒了 好的
But he's bound to be out of it. Ok.
我可以留在這嗎? 當然
May I stay here? Of course.
謝謝
Thank you.
別擔心
Don't worry.
大樓疏散後 就能護送你回家了
As soon as the building's clear, you're gonna get your own escort out of here.
別擠 一個一個來
Come on,no pushing. One at a time.
別停下 排好順序
Let's keep it moving. Nice and orderly.
這個縮寫L.C.什麼意思?
This abbreviation right here,l.C., what does that stand for?
你去哪?
Where are you going?
字條說要我按習慣行事 我歇班時都去接Jeffrey放學
The note says not to deviate from my routine, and I always pick up jeffrey on my days off.
我和你一起去
I'm gonna come with you.
說吧
Yeah.
嫌犯字條上的L.C.是指 "活著的孩子"
L.C.On the unsub's note. It stands for "living children."
你確定? 這是醫院管理用的
are you sure? It's administrative.
如果傷患需要生命維持設備 又沒有 簽署放棄搶救協議 就會標上
It's when they're afraid a patient's gonna go on life support and they don't have a dnr order.
Reid?
嫌犯會不會是說Barton醫生才是目標?
What if the unsub was trying to tell dr. Barton that he is actually the target
他的兒子將失去父親?
and that he's gonna leave his son without a father?
Barton!
醫生!
Doctor!
Reid? 回答我 Reid?
Reid? Answer me. Reid?
我是FBI特別探員Emily Prentiss
This is special agent emily prentiss from the fbi.
馬上派警察和救護車到弗吉尼亞州 麥克林 肯辛通路120號
I need police and an ambulance to 120 kensington road, mclean,virginia.
發生槍擊 探員可能受傷
Shots fired, federal agent possibly down.
你中槍了嗎? 沒有
Are you hit? No.
把槍拿過來 槍
Get my gun. My gun.
快離開他! 離開他!
Get away from him! Get away from him.
一定要趴下 不要保護他
Whatever you do,stay down. Don't protect him.
放下槍!
Drop the gun!
他殺了我兒子! 他沒殺你兒子!
He killed my son! He did not kill your son.
你兒子死於車禍 站起來!
Your son was killed by a car accident. Stand up!
再說一次 我不想對你開槍 快放下槍
I'm gonna ask you again, I do not want to shoot you, please drop the gun.
起來 你個懦夫!
Stand up,you coward!
Meyers先生 聽我說 都結束了
Mr. Meyers,listen to me. All right,it's over.
Barton醫生沒害死你兒子
Dr. Barton did not kill your son.
你兒子死於車禍
Your son was killed by a car.
他不會希望看到這種情況吧?
And this is not what he would want. Ok?
所以放下槍吧 拜託
So drop the gun. Please.
別開槍
Don't do it.
對不起
I'm sorry.
我沒事 去看他 去看他
I'm fine. Go to him. Go to him.
把他的槍踢開 別讓槍挨著他
Kick his gun away. Make sure his gun's not near him.
不 別碰我
No,don't touch me.
我不想活了 別碰我
Oh,i want to die. Oh,don't touch me.
我要幫你止血 好嗎?
I need to stop the bleeding,ok?
讓我死吧
Let me die.
醫生快到了 你能把他穩定下來嗎?
The medics are almost here. Can you keep him stabilized?
應該可以
Yes,i think so.
堅持住 他們來了
Hold on,hold on, they're right here.
急救就來了 堅持住
Help is coming,all right? Hold on,hold on.
我們需要靠背板和護頸圈
We need a backboard and a ccollar.
來了
Coming right up.
壓住這
Put pressure on this right here.
打給急診室 告訴他們傷者胸腔中彈
Call ahead to the e.R., tell them they got a gsw to the thoracic cavity
立即送手術室
and have him redlined to the o.R.Stat.
別碰我
Don't touch me.
子彈好像穿透了
Looks like it went clean through.
你剛剛救了他的命
You might have just saved his life.
壓住這 好嗎?
Keep pressure on this,ok?
我沒事 快去看你兒子 我沒事 快去
I'm good,i'm fine. Go to your son. I'm good. I'm fine. Go.
Jeffrey 你沒事吧?
Jeffrey. You ok?
我沒事
Yeah,fine.
我們送你去醫院
We'll get you to a hospital.
你們快聯繫Emily 打給Emily
You need to find emily. Call emily.
她在哪
Where is she?
Hotch出事了
Something's happened to hotch.
他還在昏迷
He still isn't conscious yet.
你確定是Foyet干的嗎?
You sure it was foyet?
他有Morgan的證件
He had morgan's credentials.
安保攝像頭拍到他了嗎?
Did they catch him on the security cam?
可以看到他把Hotch弄下車 但只有入口有攝像頭
You could see him dropping hotch off, but the camera's only on the entrance,
所以不知道他離開醫院後 往哪個方向走了
so I have no idea what direction he went once he left the hospital.
他送Hotch到急診 沒道理啊
It doesn't make sense for him to have brought hotch to the e.R.
Foyet要的是權利和操縱
We know foyet gets off on power and control.
也許他就是想說 Hotch的命握在他手
Maybe what he wants is for hotch to know his life was in his hands.
他不來醫院冒險 也能做到
He could do that without risking the hospital.
探員 他醒了
Agents,he's waking up.
記住 他還很虛弱 別勉強他
Remember,he's weak. Don't push him.
我在哪?
Where am i?
在醫院
In the hospital.
我怎麼會在這?
How did I get here?
Foyet送你來的
Foyet drove you.
你記得發生什麼事了嗎?
Can you remember what happened?
你應該做那個交易
You should have made a deal.
他拿走了什麼? 什麼意思?
What did he take? ******
惡魔獵手每次都拿走受害者的東西
The reaper always takes something from his victims.
知道他拿了什麼嗎?
Do we know what he took?
你的日程本少了一頁通訊錄 B開頭的
There was a page missing from your day planner in the address section, the bs.
他留下了什麼?
What did he leave?
不知道
I don't know.
他也會留下東西給受害人
He also leaves something with his victims.
整個公寓我都看了 沒有什麼異常
I looked over your whole apartment. Nothing felt out of place.
我的衣服呢？
Where are my clothes?
Haley娘家姓Brooks
Haley's maiden name is brooks.
怕信息落到別人手 我就把她列在B開頭那欄了
I always listed her in the bs in my personal information in case it fell into the wrong hands.
他知道他們住哪了
He knows where they live.
Haley不接電話
haley's not answering.
Garcia 在
Garcia. Right here.
派FBI特警部隊到Hotch原住址 馬上
I need fbi s.W.A.T.Deployed to hotch's old address. Do it now.
天啊 他要對付Haley和Jack?
Oh,god,do you think he's going after haley and jack?
我不知道 先派特警隊過去
I don't know. Just send a s.W.A.T.Team.
讓他們等候指令 我們馬上就到
Tell them to wait for instructions. We're on our way.
他們在那接應
Consider them there.
一會不知結果如何 我們要有心理準備
We need to be prepared for what we might find.
Foyet沒有殺掉Hotch 肯定有原因
Foyet kept hotch alive. He wouldn't do that without a reason.
你應該做那個交易
*******
這是我側寫的結果嗎? 不能對我表現出恐懼？
Is this part of my profileyou can't show me fear?
你看不見恐懼 是因為我並不怕你
If you don't see fear, maybe it's because i'm not afraid of you.
說得跟真的一樣
You said that like you actually meant it.
我的朋友Morgan探員現在怎樣?
How's my friend agent morgan?
你是想殺我 還是想玩遊戲?
Are you here to kill me, or are you here to play games?
你覺得呢
You tell me.
指明我的行為根源
Enlighten me about my behavior.
告訴我 我會用這個嗎?
So tell me, would I use this?
出什麼事了? 不知道
What happened? I don't know.
Hotchner探員 聽得見嗎 Hotchner探員?
Agent hotchner. Can you hear me? Agent hotchner?
我沒事 麻煩你先離開病房
I'm ok. I'm gonna need you to step out of the room.
慢慢吸氣
Breathe in slowly.
呼氣
And exhale.
後門就緒?
Ready in back?
就緒
Ready.
進!
Go!
天哪! 沒事 沒事
Oh,my god! It's ok. It's ok.
你們這是幹什麼? 沒事的 不要慌
What are you doing here? It's ok. Everything's ok.
我們找到她了 發生了什麼事?
We got her. What's going on?
屋媮晹釦O人嗎?
Is there anyone else in the house?
沒別人了
No,there's no one here.
Haley Jack呢?
Haley,where's jack?
他在一個朋友家堛
He's at a friend's house for a play date.
我們得接他回來
We need to get him back here.
待會兒跟你詳細解釋
We'll explain everything.
Aaron在哪? 在醫院
Where's aaron? He's in the hospital.
什麼? Haley 拜託了 打電話給Jack
What? Haley,please. Call for jack.
告訴他們我現在去接他
Tell them i'm on the way to pick him up.
我保證會向你解釋清楚
I promise you we'll explain.
現在就給他打電話
Call for him right now.
地址發給我
Text me the address.
告訴我Aaron怎麼了
Tell me what happened to aaron.
他們會殺了你
They will kill you.
別說話 你失血過多
Don't speak. You lost a lot of blood.
留點氧氣吧
You'll need your oxygen.
知道瞭解人體到何種程度 才能不斷刺傷自己 還保住命嗎?
Do you know how much you have to study the human body to stab yourself repeatedly and not die?
不是顯擺 但我怎麼也算個行家
I don't want to brag, but i'm somewhat of an expert.
想看看我的傷疤嗎?
Do you want to see my scars?
怎樣? 還喜歡嗎?
What do you think? You like 'em?
你也會變這樣的
Yours are gonna look just the same.
我的人..
My team...
你的人
Your team.
要是我不想被抓 你的人根本抓不到我
Your team didn't catch me until I wanted them to.
現在你說了不算 別傻了
You're not in charge, so don't be foolish.
盡量放鬆些
Now try to relax.
你的身體會變得麻木
Your body will go numb.
只要你放鬆...
And it goes in so much easier...
刀子進去就容易多了
If you relax.
最難受的可不是痛暈過去
The hard part is not passing out from the pain.
我知道側寫員認為刀刺是對性行為的代替
Now,i understand that profilers think that stabbing is a substitution for the act of sex.
要是罪犯性無能 就會選擇用刀來代替
That if somebody's impotent, they'll use a knife instead.
你覺得是嗎 Hotchner探員?
Is that what you think, agent hotchner?
也許這次會改變你的側寫手法
Maybe this will change the way that you profile.
他們沒事
They're safe.
有必要這樣嗎?
Is this really necessary?
恐怕是的
I'm afraid so.
要多久? 我不知道
For how long? I don't know.
媽咪!
Mommy!
他們讓我開警笛玩!
They let me turn on the siren!
太厲害了 寶貝! 好玩嗎?
Wow,that's so great,baby! Did you have fun?
我去Jack房間幫忙收拾行李 好的
I'll help start a bag in jack's room. Ok.
你玩了幾次哇?
How many times did you run it?
幾次? 3次?
How many times? 3?
你去了我家?
You were at my place, right?
看出他怎麼進去的嗎?
Could you tell how he got in?
我不知道
I'm not sure.
想談談發生的事嗎?
Do you want to talk about what happened?
我不記得了
I don't know.
只記得他刺的第一刀 其他一片空白
After he stabbed me the first time, it all goes blank.
你覺得怎麼樣?
How do you feel?
我會好起來的
I'm gonna be ok.
他們跟你解釋怎麼回事沒?
Did they explain to you what's happening?
他們說聯邦執法署直接 從這兒接走我們 進行保護性監管
They said the marshals service is taking us straight from here and putting us into protective custody.
Haley 對不起
Haley,i'm sorry.
他們要帶我們去哪?
Do you know where they're gonna take us?
我不知道 但這才是重點
No,i don't. And that's the point.
我不能知道你們去哪
I can't know where you're going.
只要你一聯繫別人 他就會找到你
If you have any contact with anyone, then he could track you.
Jack要上學見朋友 我也要工作
Jack has school. He has friends. I have a job now.
我知道 對不起
I know. And i'm sorry.
我們一定抓住他 到時你們就能回來了
We will catch him and you'll come back,
我保證會用盡餘生來補償你
and I promise that I will spend the rest of my life making this up to you.
你肯定我們現在有危險?
Are you sure that we're in danger?
對
Yes.
那你呢? 你安全嗎?
And what about you? Are you gonna be safe?
他想看我痛苦
He wants to see me suffer.
他知道 與兒子分別比殺了我更有用
Knowing that my son is out there and that I can't see him is better than killing me.
那我要怎麼跟Jack說?
What am I supposed to say to jack?
告訴他這是度假 不會很久的
Tell him it's a vacation and that it's not gonna be for very long.
都沒個相識的人幫忙 我要怎麼保護他?
How am I supposed to keep him safe if there is no one I know to help me?
Haley 你很堅強
Haley,you're strong.
你接受了我的工作 幾乎獨自撫養Jack
You lived with me in this job, and you've practically raised jack all by yourself.
你是個偉大的母親
You're a great mother.
你能抓到他嗎?
Can you catch this man?
我會抓到他的
I will catch this man.
Jack想進來
Jack wants to come in.
我也想見他 但現在不合適
I want to see him,too. I just don't think it's a good idea.
我知道你是想保護他
Look,i know you're trying to protect him.
但見一面對你們都好 拜託了
But you both need this. Please.
好吧
Ok.
嘿 小傢伙 進來
Hey,buddy. Come on in.
好勒
All right.
別擔心 沒事的
Don't worry. It's ok.
醫生檢查了 我一點事都沒有
The doctors made sure that i'm completely fine.
媽媽告訴你沒 你們要去旅行?
Did mommy tell you that you two are gonna take a trip?
說了
Yeah.
那這陣子我們見不著了
So i'm not gonna see you for a while.
為什麼?
Why?
想想看爸爸出差工作的時候
Well,think about it like when daddy goes away for work.
只是這次換你和媽媽離開
Only this time you and mommy get to go someplace.
記得我每次離開說的話嗎?
But what do I tell you every time I go away?
你愛我 勝過這世上的一切
You love me. More than anything in the world.
你沒事嗎?
Are you ok?
我為你而驕傲 每一天都是
I'm very proud of you. Every single day.
我們很快會見面的 好嗎? 好
I'll see you soon,ok? Ok.
你要照顧好媽媽 知道嗎? 知道
You take care of mom,ok? Ok.
我知道Aaron很擔心
I know aaron's worried.
告訴他 我會把他們當家人來保護的
Tell him i'll protect them like they're my own.
我剛跟Spence談過 他沒事的
I just talked to spence. He's gonna be fine.
不過得有好一陣子撐枴杖了
He's gonna have to be on crutches for a while,
不過他說反正踹門是Morgan的活
but he said kicking down doors is morgan's job,anyway.
Foyet拿你證件 跟這件事一點關係沒有
You know,foyet having your credentials had nothing to do with any of this.
他只是想這樣來折磨你
It was just his way of trying to torture you.
我知道 Foyet要的是權利和操縱
Yeah,i know. Foyet's about power and control.
他等著看我崩潰...
He was hoping to watch me fall apart,and...
現在他想毀掉Hotch
Now he wants to destroy hotch.
沒錯 這就是他的計劃 現在我們要阻止他
Exactly. That's his plan, and now we fight it.
你聽說今早的事了嗎?
Did you hear what happened this morning?
沒有
No.
有個案子
We had a situation.
不明疑犯已經殺害兩人
Unsub had already killed 2 people.
還要求一個男人兒子當誘餌 否則還會繼續動手
Said he was gonna keep killing unless a man used his son as bait.
然後呢?
What happened?
我們保護了那個男孩 給出了側寫
We kept the boy safe. Worked the profile.
圓滿大結局
It was a happy ending.
知道我為什麼告訴你嗎?
Do you know why i'm telling you this?
知道
Yes.
你的團隊在過去幾小時辦到的 世上沒有其他人做得到
No other group in the world could have pulled off what your team did in a matter of hours.
我很感激你說這些話 Dave
I appreciate what you're trying to do,dave.
我們會抓到Foyet的
We'll get foyet.
我向Haley承諾我們會抓到他 但事實是
I promised haley that we would get him, but the truth is,
要是他不再殺戮 我們根本找不到他
if he stops killing, we have no way of tracking him.
之前他停止殺戮10年 只是為了欣賞 Shaunessy的生活分崩瓦解
He stopped killing for 10 years just for the pleasure of watching shaunessy's life fall apart.
10年後 Jack還會記得我什麼?
What's jack gonna remember about me in 10 years?
Hotch 看著我
Hotch,look at me.
我現在告訴你 我們一定會抓到他的
I'm telling you, we'll get him.
犯罪心理 第五季 第1集
== 結束 ==
Criminal Minds Season05 Episode01 Nameless, Faceless